R. Scott Vivilecchia

144 County Rd., Bourne, Massachusetts +1 617 678 4222 rscott@vi-vi.io linkedin.com/in/vi-vi-io PORTFOLIO - https://vi-vi.io

A Visual Storyteller with over a decade of experience delivering poignant, strategy-driven content. I'm proficient in ideation, graphic design, all phases of video production, and front-end web development. With a distinctive blend of creative and technical expertise, I create content that educates, informs, and entertains.

Core Competencies

Graphic Design:

- Layout
- Typography
- Illustration
- Photo Editing

Digital Design:

- Responsive fluid grid layouts
- UI/UX. Interaction design
- SEO, Google Analytics
- ADA compliance

Video production:

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES 6

YouTube, Vimeo, Kaltura API's

• SVG, <canvas>, and GIF animation

- Storyboarding
- Directing/Interviewing
- Videography/Photography
- Editing, Color, Motion GFX

Web tech: WordPress, Drupal, Jekyll/Gatstby, Git/GitHub, Continuous Integration/Deployment, PHP, mySQL, SASS/LESS, Bootstrap 3/4/5

Software: Adobe Creative Suite (Premiere, After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Davinci Resolve, Microsoft Office, Google Suite

General skills: Copy writing, Committed collaborator, Creative problem-solving, Strong attention to detail, Work independently, Al enhanced workflow, File management, Manage multiple projects, Mac/Windows/Linux

Work Experience

Designer, Filmmaker & Content Creator

VIVI Productions

2019 - Present

- · Use a well-honed research process, meticulous strategic planning and thoughtful visual storytelling to create results-driven video and multimedia content for a diverse range of clients
- · Consult on strategy, trends and tech requirements for social media platforms and the web, leading to deeper engagement and increased call to action follow-through on campaigns
- Partner with clients and their subject matter experts throughout the entire product life cycle strategy, production, distribution, and evaluation
- · Build consistent brand identities across channels, increasing recognition and customer loyalty

Video Production Specialist

2013 - 2019

Voya Financial

- Collaborated with Fortune 500 and large government clients on award-winning educational videos that drove engagement with their unique employee benefit plans
- · Worked with the executive leadership team to plan, create and deliver engaging, meaningful video content that moved the needle on hundreds of sales pitches and marketing campaigns
- Contributed to the evolution of brand standards for video and web content

Creative Services Designer

2004 - 2013

Voya Financial, ING, CitiStreet

- · Designed impactful visual assets, including videos, web apps and PowerPoint presentations, to support sales meetings, leading to retirement plan conversions valued at Billions of dollars in assets under management, and positioning the company as a leader in the industry.
- · Collaborated with the Plan Participant Education team to develop a diverse library of client-branded web apps that led to a 12% average increase in retirement plan participation

Education